# 今天我过生日就烤2个兔子简简单单的烤一下
I will grill two rabbits simply as today is my birthday
# 这个兔子我已经改好刀了
These are cut well
# 现在准备一下姜葱把兔子腌一下
Now let’s prepare some green onion and ginger and cure the rabbit a little bit
# 稍微腌几分钟就够了
Curing a couple of mins is enough
# 切两三根大葱
Cut two or three leeks
# 大葱像这样不切断
The leek is not cut off like this
# 切开就可以更容易入味
The cutted leek would release more flavour
# 如果切碎了等下很难挑
It’s hard to pick them out if they are fully cut off
# 我们现在只倒了料酒跟酱油
So far we only added cooking wine and soy sauce
# 我觉得这样都差不多够了
I think it’s good for now
# 因为待会我边烤的时候会再边刷酱料上去
Because I will brush some spice on it when grilling
# 这个肉我们大概腌了几分钟了
We have cured this meat for a couple of mins
# 直接把它上烤架吧
Directly put it on the grill net
# 因为我们这边吃兔子的话不喜欢腌得很咸
Because we don’t like curing rabbit to be too salty
# 腌淡一点 待会再上麻辣味 再上咸味
Cure it with less salt. Add spice and salt later
# 这样子就可以了
Just like this is OK
# 放下去慢慢烤
Put it down and grill it slowly
# 先干烤一会
Firstly grill it without any spice
# 干烤得表面有点熟了再刷其他的酱料
After the surface was grilled well, brush the spices
# 你估计要烤好久 四伯爷
Can you estimate how long we need to grill it? Uncle.
# 烤一个多小时
One hour or a little bit more
# 个多小时啊 我估计也要差不多
More than one hour? I guess the same
# 你扇我扇是一样的撒
Fanning by you or by myself is the same
# 我给你扇
Let me fan you
# 哎呀 我享受啊
Aya, How enjoyable I am
# 啊
Ah
# 好嘛 我享受哈
Alright, I’d like to enjoy it
# 我四伯爷说他要用这个尖刀划一下
My uncle said he will use this sharp knife to cut it a little bit
# 这里都熟了你看 贴上去了这个
See this is cooked well, the one stick on the grill net
# 这个已经熟了
This one is grilled well
# 就放点酱油这个底味啊已经有百分之四五十了吧
The soy sauce let it contain about forty or fifty percent of foundation flavor
# 哎呀 好烫 OK
Aya so hot OK
# 现在我们这个烤起来就更快了
Now the grilling would be faster
# 你那个还要烤一哈哦
This one has to be grilled a little bit more
# 这个肯定还没好撒
This one is not cooked thoroughly
# 等会夹在上面烧
We can put it in the net to grill it
# 嗯 夹在上面烤
Right, put it in the net
# 现在我们这个腰子已经快熟了 但是还差一点
Now the kidney is almost good to eat, but still underdone a little bit
# 我们这个兔子已经烤了一个小时了嘎
We have grilled these rabbits for about one hour, right?
# 一个小时多点了
A little bit more than one hour
# 我们烤了一个小时了这个兔子
We have grilled these rabbits for one hour already
# 可以看一下这个颜色
Look at the color
# 这个颜色特别的漂亮
The color is so pretty
# 大概烤个十来分钟就可以刷我们的料
We can brush our spice after 10 mins
# 撒料就可以上（桌）了
It is ready for eat once added the spice
# 待会直接把它倒出来用手把它撕开
Take it out and shred it by hand later
# 撕开之后就可以吃了
It’s ready for eat after shredded
# 非烫的你咋个撕哦 冷会儿来撕
It’s too hot to shred it by hand. Let’s do it after cooling down a little bit
# 筷子给它戳撒
Use chopsticks to shred it
# 我感觉这个兔子挺好吃的
I feel the rabbit meat must be yummy
# 这样子烤起肯定安逸哦
It must be very tasty as grilling it like this
# 肯定好吃哦
Must be tasty
# 你看这个颜色真的很漂亮
You see the color is really beautiful
# 噶
Yeah
# 嗯
# 很漂亮哦
Very beautiful
# 下次去我兄弟家弄他2只兔子来烤一下
I will take two rabbits from my brother and grill them next time
# 他最近不是开了一个兔子养殖场 好像是
He opened a rabbit farm recently, it seems like
# 下次去他家抓2只兔子
Take two rabbits from him next time
# 好了 我们这个兔子啊已经可以了
All right, our rabbit is grilled thoroughly
# 现在撒一点料上去
Put some spices on it
# 我先撒孜然粉哦四伯爷
I will firstly add some cumin powder, Uncle
# 稍微少点的
Just a little bit
# 孜然粉不关事可以稍微多点 这个是上味的
We can put more cumin powder, as it can enrich the flavor
# 撒这个海椒面
Add some chili powder
# 少点少点这个东西
Much less chili powder
# 这个是要弄盐味的不关事
This is for making it salty and doesn’t matter
# 这个不辣
This one won’t by spicy
# 这个不辣 等会辣很了
This is not spicy? It would become very spicy soon
# 这个是不辣的
This one is not spicy
# 拿个放拿一个不放嘛等会是不是
Just put chili powder in one rabbit, the other one is non-spicy, ok?
# 要得啊
Sure
# 好 那个就不放了
All right, I won’t put chili powder in that one
# 芝麻
Sesame
# 好
All right
# 我怀疑我一筷子都可以把它夹出来
I wonder whether I can take it out merely by chopstick in one time
# 可以安
Good job
# 差点掉到地上了
Nearly fell on the floor
# 哇塞 这个好脆啊
Wow this is so crispy
# 好脆哦噶
Very crispy
# 嗯
Yep
# 都听到这个脆的感觉了
I hear the scrispy sound
# 四伯爷夹来试哈看
Uncle, come and try it
# 我用手撕哦
I will use hand to shred it
# 果然特别香
It is really tasty
# 我再撒一点辣椒面上去
I will put more chili powder on it
# 这个是我自己调的一个辣椒面
This is a chili powder mixed with other spices by myself
# 这样更加够味 里面的话也有味道
This can enrich the flavor, and the inside of meat can absorb more flavor
# 你还是整的兔腿腿呀
You are eating the rabbit leg
# 嗯
Yes
# 嗯 好香哦 好吃
Yeah, smells great, yummy
# 哎呀 真的整得好吃
Aya, it’s delicious
# 我是在那儿都整饿了
I am hungry while waiting for it
# 太好吃了
Tastes heavenly
# 还安逸 我的牙口不好都整得动
Though I have a chewing difficulty I can chew it easily, great
# 是不
Really
# 是啊
Yes
# 真的还整得安逸
It’s really yummy
# 这个撕开 一撕就撕得开了
Shred this, just use your finger to shred it
# 然后这只兔子我加了很多花椒
I put a lot Sichuan pepper in this rabbit
# 这一只的话就没有加
And no Sichuan pepper in that one
# 待会这只给我老婆带回去吃
I will take that one to my wife
# 这兔肉啊
This rabbit meat, hmm
# 嗯
Yeah
# 可以
Good
# 好不好吃
Tasty?
# 好吃
Tasty
# 好了本期视频就到这里 拜拜
All right, the video ends here. Bye bye
# 拜拜
Bye Bye
# 如果可以尝试的话 自己去烤一下
If you get a chance, try to grill it
# 这个真的比（猪）肉还便宜
This is even cheaper than pork
# 好吃
Yummy
# 又香又脆 我牙口不好的我都整得动
It is crispy and full of aromatic, I can chew it even though my teeth condition is not good
# 真的这个兔子这样子烤起安逸
Indeed, grilling rabbit in this way is amazing